<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-14T23:54:49-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mama’s Coding Dreams</title><subtitle>A lovely wonderful blog that records my journey of coding while my baby falls asleep.</subtitle><author><name>Michelle CH Lin</name></author><entry><title type="html">A Journey Into Deep Learning - Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/data%20science/Setup-Python-Tensorflow-Environment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Journey Into Deep Learning - Week 1" /><published>2020-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/data%20science/Setup-Python-Tensorflow-Environment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/data%20science/Setup-Python-Tensorflow-Environment/">&lt;p&gt;As I am thinking of self-learning Machine Learning (ML), I want to quickly pick up the skills and foundation of Python. &lt;em&gt;(I used more with R, Matlab during my PhD work)&lt;/em&gt;. So, since last year when I was at 9-month pregnancy, I’ve completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/course/python-for-data-science-and-machine-learning-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;Python for Data Science and ML Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;, instructed by Jose Portilla. Today, I have some sorts of feeling that I know what I was doing as a mom (~ 6 months after giving birth). Then, I grab and read a book &lt;em&gt;The Algebra of Happiness&lt;/em&gt;, make a coffee, and open my MacBook - thinking, I’d like to continue to learn more about ML as I have been always fascinated with data. In between my baby sleep-wake cycle, I read and code and write down what I did, even just a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday March 14, the world is fighting with coronavirus and my world is thrilling that I start the journey of learning new things, from this course &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/course/complete-tensorflow-2-and-keras-deep-learning-bootcamp/&quot;&gt;Tensorflow 2 and Keras Deep Learning Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, I can start making fun project soon through applying what I’ve learned every single time I have when my baby fall asleep and/or take a nap. Here I’d like to make notes of every steps and accomplishment, &lt;strong&gt;even just a little bit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t hate machine learning for being simple. Levers are simple too, but they can move the world.
-Cassie Kozyrkov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1-314-tensorflow-setup-and-install&quot;&gt;Day-1 (3/14): TensorFlow Setup and Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the notes for myself:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downland Python 3.7 Version from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/&quot;&gt;Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; for MacOS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a folder, named “TensorFlow” under Desktop/Gitproject/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downland the class materials into the created folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I should do next time for STARTING the course:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;% conda activate mytfenv&lt;/code&gt;the TensorFlow Environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Locate the path in terminal like:&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;% cd Desktop/Gitproject/TensorFlow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get into virtual env using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;% jupyter notebook&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Michelle CH Lin</name></author><category term="Udemy" /><category term="Python" /><category term="TensorFlow" /><summary type="html">As I am thinking of self-learning Machine Learning (ML), I want to quickly pick up the skills and foundation of Python. (I used more with R, Matlab during my PhD work). So, since last year when I was at 9-month pregnancy, I’ve completed Python for Data Science and ML Bootcamp, instructed by Jose Portilla. Today, I have some sorts of feeling that I know what I was doing as a mom (~ 6 months after giving birth). Then, I grab and read a book The Algebra of Happiness, make a coffee, and open my MacBook - thinking, I’d like to continue to learn more about ML as I have been always fascinated with data. In between my baby sleep-wake cycle, I read and code and write down what I did, even just a little bit. On Saturday March 14, the world is fighting with coronavirus and my world is thrilling that I start the journey of learning new things, from this course Tensorflow 2 and Keras Deep Learning Bootcamp. Hopefully, I can start making fun project soon through applying what I’ve learned every single time I have when my baby fall asleep and/or take a nap. Here I’d like to make notes of every steps and accomplishment, even just a little bit. Don’t hate machine learning for being simple. Levers are simple too, but they can move the world. -Cassie Kozyrkov Day-1 (3/14): TensorFlow Setup and Install Here are the notes for myself: Downland Python 3.7 Version from Anaconda for MacOS Create a folder, named “TensorFlow” under Desktop/Gitproject/ Downland the class materials into the created folder What I should do next time for STARTING the course: Activate % conda activate mytfenvthe TensorFlow Environment Locate the path in terminal like:% cd Desktop/Gitproject/TensorFlow Get into virtual env using % jupyter notebook</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">100 Days Of Code Challenge- D11-20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-2nd-Week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 Days Of Code Challenge- D11-20" /><published>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-2nd-Week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-2nd-Week/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the log for the 2nd week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michelle CH Lin</name></author><category term="100DaysOfCode" /><category term="CSS" /><category term="HTML" /><summary type="html">This is the log for the 2nd week:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Notes For CSS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/Notes-To-Self-CSS-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Notes For CSS" /><published>2020-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web%20design/Notes-To-Self-CSS-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/Notes-To-Self-CSS-1/">&lt;p&gt;I used to design webpages for hosting Taiwan Ocean Science Meeting Events while I worked at Academic Sinica, Taipei (7 years ago). So, CSS is not completely new to me. Given that CSS has changed quite substantially in the last few years, participating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/michellechlin/full/mdJEVOv&quot;&gt;Product Landing Project&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/strong&gt; is really good for myself to refresh the knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even if CSS is very small part of what I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I did not need to memorize every CSS syntax and values; however, making notes will make CSS much easier to use in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css-layout---float-and-clear&quot;&gt;CSS Layout - float and clear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;float&lt;/code&gt; is used to positioning and formatting content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;clear&lt;/code&gt; is used to specify what elements can float beside the cleared element and on which side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;box-sizing&lt;/code&gt; defines how width and height of the element&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;overflow&lt;/code&gt; specifies what happens if content overflows an elements’s box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;clearfix&lt;/code&gt; works well when you want to control the margins and padding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;::after&lt;/code&gt; is pseudo-element&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;style&amp;gt;
* {  
  box-sizing: border-box;
}

.image-container {
  float: left;
  width: 50%; /*for two images*/
  padding: 5px; /* build space between the images */
}

.clearfix::after {
  content: &quot;&quot;;
  clear: both;
  display: table;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-for-future-uses&quot;&gt;Resources for future uses:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/default.asp&quot;&gt;w3schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://htmlcolorcodes.com/color-chart/&quot;&gt;HTML Color Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Michelle CH Lin</name></author><category term="FreeCodeCamp" /><category term="CSS" /><category term="HTML" /><summary type="html">I used to design webpages for hosting Taiwan Ocean Science Meeting Events while I worked at Academic Sinica, Taipei (7 years ago). So, CSS is not completely new to me. Given that CSS has changed quite substantially in the last few years, participating the Product Landing Project in FreeCodeCamp is really good for myself to refresh the knowledge. Even if CSS is very small part of what I need to do. I know I did not need to memorize every CSS syntax and values; however, making notes will make CSS much easier to use in the future. CSS Layout - float and clear float is used to positioning and formatting content. clear is used to specify what elements can float beside the cleared element and on which side. box-sizing defines how width and height of the element overflow specifies what happens if content overflows an elements’s box clearfix works well when you want to control the margins and padding ::after is pseudo-element &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; * { box-sizing: border-box; } .image-container { float: left; width: 50%; /*for two images*/ padding: 5px; /* build space between the images */ } .clearfix::after { content: &quot;&quot;; clear: both; display: table; } ## Resources for future uses: w3schools HTML Color Code</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">100 Days Of Code Challenge- Day1-10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-1st-Week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 Days Of Code Challenge- Day1-10" /><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-1st-Week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/web%20design/100Days-of-Code-1st-Week/">&lt;style&gt;
li{
  list-style-type: disc;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Motivation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After quitting my job from &lt;em&gt;Application (R&amp;amp;D) Scientist&lt;/em&gt; at Bay instrument, I kinda slow down my career development and become a stay-at-home mom. I do really enjoy the time with my baby boy, but the feeling of depression and anxiety comes and goes. Being a full-time mom is lack of appreciation or a missing sense of accomplishment compared to what I did before as PhD and/or Scientist. So, I want to change the daily schedule for myself, for a better future, after my boy go to preK. Here I commit myself to take &lt;a href=&quot;https://https://www.100daysofcode.com/&quot;&gt;100 Days of Code Challenge&lt;/a&gt; where I spend at least one hour coding for 100 days (in a row).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jane Goodall once said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What you do makes a difference, and you have to decide
what kind of difference you want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My big motivation for taking this challenge is &lt;strong&gt;Learn to Code&lt;/strong&gt; to make a difference in changing people’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Is My Main Goals:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;1. Complete the &lt;strong&gt;FreeCampCode&lt;/strong&gt; Web Certificate&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;2. Have a capability to customize the design of a blog&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Is The Log For Day1-10:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 1:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learn Basic HTML &amp;amp; HTML5&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create my Github page&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 2:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continue to Learn HTML &amp;amp; HTML5&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Setup local work environment with Atom, GitKraken&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 3:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn CSS Style&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn Jekyll blogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 4:
  &lt;ul&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Done 35% of Applied Visual Design &lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Get familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/step-by-step/08-blogging/&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;Jekyll blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 5:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn Applied Visual Design&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn Jekyll Theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day 6:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Completed Applied Visual Design&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jekyll Theme with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&quot; alt=&quot;mmistakes&quot;&gt;@mmistakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Learn git and work jekyll blog in the local&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day7:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Completed Design Principles &amp;amp; CSS Flexbox&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quarterly  done with CSS Grid &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;Day8-10:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Building up the 1st project line by line - Tribute Page for Jane Goodall &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/michellechlin/full/eYNNrNj&quot; alt=&quot;Tribute Page&quot;&gt;Tribute Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.likeagirl.io/100-days-of-code-challenge-completed-bbce87f04c00&quot;&gt;Her story of completing 100DaysOfCode&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codenewbie.org/podcast/100-days-of-code&quot;&gt;Podcast of #100DaysOfCode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michelle CH Lin</name></author><category term="100DaysOfCode" /><category term="CSS" /><category term="HTML" /><summary type="html">My Motivation: After quitting my job from Application (R&amp;amp;D) Scientist at Bay instrument, I kinda slow down my career development and become a stay-at-home mom. I do really enjoy the time with my baby boy, but the feeling of depression and anxiety comes and goes. Being a full-time mom is lack of appreciation or a missing sense of accomplishment compared to what I did before as PhD and/or Scientist. So, I want to change the daily schedule for myself, for a better future, after my boy go to preK. Here I commit myself to take 100 Days of Code Challenge where I spend at least one hour coding for 100 days (in a row). Jane Goodall once said: What you do makes a difference, and you have to decide what kind of difference you want to make. My big motivation for taking this challenge is Learn to Code to make a difference in changing people’s life. This Is My Main Goals: 1. Complete the FreeCampCode Web Certificate 2. Have a capability to customize the design of a blog This Is The Log For Day1-10: Day 1: Learn Basic HTML &amp;amp; HTML5 Create my Github page Day 2: Continue to Learn HTML &amp;amp; HTML5 Setup local work environment with Atom, GitKraken Day 3: Learn CSS Style Learn Jekyll blogging Day 4: Done 35% of Applied Visual Design Get familiar with Jekyll blog Day 5: Learn Applied Visual Design Learn Jekyll Theme Day 6: Completed Applied Visual Design Jekyll Theme with @mmistakes Learn git and work jekyll blog in the local Day7: Completed Design Principles &amp;amp; CSS Flexbox Quarterly done with CSS Grid Day8-10: Building up the 1st project line by line - Tribute Page for Jane Goodall Tribute Page Resources: Her story of completing 100DaysOfCode FreeCodeCamp Podcast of #100DaysOfCode</summary></entry></feed>